Inventory of the Gesamtverband Deutscher Antikommunistischer Vereinigungen records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Group II, Monitoring Reports, 1933-1944.; (13 linear feet) (Box 176-206)
  - Country or region
    - Pakistan, 1937 (File 184: 15)
    - Palestine (and Syria), 1934-1944 (File 184: 16-18)
    - Paraguay, 1936-1939 (File 185: 1)
    - Peru, 1936-1938 (File 185: 2)
    - Philippines, 1937 (File 185: 3)
    - Portugal, 1935-1938 (File 185: 4-8)
    - Romania, 1936-1944 (File 185: 9-15)
    - Singapore, 1937 (File 185: 16)
    - South Africa, 1939 (File 185: 17)
    - Soviet Union, 1935-1944 (File 185: 18-21)
    - Soviet Union, 1935-1944 (File 186: 1-10)
    - Spain, 1934-1936 (File 186: 11-20)
    - Spain, 1934-1943 (Box 187-193)
    - Spain, 1934-1943 (File 194: 1-14)
    - Sweden, 1933-1944 (File 194: 15-20)
    - Sweden, 1933-1944 (File 195: 1-8)
    - Switzerland, 1934-1944 (File 195: 9-23)
    - Switzerland, 1936-1939 (File 196: 1-2)
    - Syria. See Palestine
    - Thailand, 1938-1944 (File 196: 3-7)
    - Tunis, 1936-1938 (File 196: 8)
    - Turkey, 1937-1940 (File 196: 9-12)
    - Uruguay, 1935-1939 (File 196: 13-18)
    - Venezuela, 1935-1939 (File 196: 19-20)
  - Topic
    - Aktion Brasol (File 197: 1-2)
    - Astrology (File 197: 3-5)
    - Catholicism, 1936-1938 (File 197: 6-8)
    - Communist International, 1939 (File 197: 9)
    - Imperialism, 1932-1936 (File 197: 10-12)
    - League of Nations, 1936-1937 (File 197: 13)
    - Little Entente, 1937 (File 197: 14-15)
    - Locarno Powers, 1936-1937 (File 197: 16)
    - Norden Blatt, 1939-1940 (File 198: 1-8)
    - Pan American Conference, 1936-1939 (File 198: 9)
    - Reichspropagandaleitung, 1938-1939 (File 198: 10-17)
    - Südosten Blatt, 1939-1940 (File 199: 1-5)
    - Übersee Blatt, 1939-1940 (File 199: 6-8)
    - Weisse Bewegung, 1942-1943 (File 199: 9)
    - Westen Blatt, 1939 (File 199: 10-15)
  - Unsorted material (Box 200-206)
- Group III, Manuscripts, 1938-1944.; (1.25 linear feet) (Box 207-209)
  Typed or mimeographed manuscripts on Soviet activities, in German and French.
  Arranged in three parts, A, B, and D. Part C has been moved to Group I, box 172
  - Part A, undated
    - Berühmte Männer des Krieges: Josef Wissarionowitsch Stalin, undated (Folder 207: 1)
  - Part B, 1917-1944
    - Akademie der Wissenschaften der U.d.S.S.R., 1943 July (Folder 207: 2)
    - Hochschule und Wissenschaft unter dem Bolschewismus, undated (Folder 207: 3)
    - Das Wesen des sozialen Systems des Bolschewismus, 1944 September 12 (Folder 207: 4)
    - Das Sowjetkalifat, undated (Folder 207: 5)
    - Der Bauer in der Sowjetunion, undated (Folder 207: 6)
    - Die Sowjetindustrie (Materialzusammenstellung), undated (Folder 207: 7)
    - Opfer des Bolschewismus, undated (Folder 207: 8)
    - Der letzte Hammerschlag, oder Wiedergegebenes Land, by Hans-Wolfgang Hillers, undated (Folder 207: 9)
    - Übersicht der Links-Bewegung in den Niederlanden (Folder 207: 10)
    - Die Beziehungen Englands zur Sowjetunion Lagebericht, Stichtag:, 1944 August 1 (Folder 207: 11)
    - Gorki auf den Solowki, by Professor Solowetzki, undated (Folder 207: 12)
    - In den Krallen der N.K.V.D. (G.P.U.), by Kozlow, 1942 January 7 (Folder 207: 13)
    - Strafgefangener Nr. 6 311 965, by Kajetan Klug, undated (Folder 207: 14)
    - G.P.U., by Carlo v. Kügelgen, undated (Folder 207: 15)
    - Die wirklichen Kriegsziele und ihre Maskierung, by Larionow, undated (Folder 207: 16)
    - Die Entrechteten, by E. L., undated (Folder 207: 17)
    - Durch dunkle Nacht, by Nikolai Moskwitsch, undated (Folder 207: 18)
    - Ziel und Richtung der Kriegsvorbereitung (Die sowjetische Reaktion auf die deutsche Ostpolitik seit 1933), undated (Folder 207: 19)
    - Beziehungen zwischen der Sowjetunion und Litauen 1920-1940, undated.; Chronological list (Folder 207: 20)
    - Beziehungen zwischen der Sowjetunion und Lettland 1919-1940, undated.; Chronological list (Folder 207: 21)
    - Beziehungen zwischen der Sowjetunion und Estland 1917-1940, undated.; Chronological list (Folder 207: 22)
    - Völker, hört das Signal! Ein Jahr Bolschewismus in den Baltischen Staaten, undated (Folder 207: 23)
    - Plutokratie - Judentum - Bolschewismus, undated (Folder 207: 24)
    - Die Protokolle der Weisen von Zion: Das Programm der internationalen Geheimregierung. Übersetzt aus dem Russischen nach S. A. Nilus und mit einer Einführung versehen, 1944 (Folder 207: 25)
    - Die Dämmerung der Orthodoxie, by E. L., undated (Folder 207: 26)
    - Die wirklichen Kriegsziele und ihre Maskierung, by Larionow, undated (Folder 208: 1)
    - Räte für Kirchenangelegenheiten, by E. L., undated (Folder 208: 2)
    - Der letzte Aufruf des Metropoliten Sergius von Litauen und Wilna, by E. L., undated (Folder 208: 3)
    - Kirche und Revolution, by E. L., undated (Folder 208: 4)
    - Die geistige Innenfront, by Prof. Syrjansky, undated (Folder 208: 5)
    - Die Bekennerbischöfe und der Patriarch Sergius, undated (Folder 208: 6)
    - "Der Todfeind des Christentums,", undated (Folder 208: 7)
    - Bischof Nikolai von Rostow, 1943 December 18 (Folder 208: 8)
    - "Aussprüche führender Geistlicher gegen den Kommunismus," (Folder 208: 9)
    - Der Bolschewismus im Kampf gegen Gott 1917-1942, undated (Folder 208: 10)
    - Stalin als Mensch und Politiker, undated (Folder 208: 11)
    - Stalin als Reformator, undated (Folder 208: 12)
    - Die ukrainische Intelligenz - Ein Opfer des bolschewistischen Terrors, undated (Folder 208: 13)
    - Die Jeshow-Epoche im Leben der Sowjet-Union: Die grosse Terrorwelle 1937-1938, undated (Folder 208: 14)
    - Totenparade, undated (Folder 208: 15)
    - Flüchtlinge, undated (Folder 208: 16)
    - L'Assaut des Peuples, undated (Folder 208: 17)
    - Si L'Europe était bolchévisée, undated (Folder 208: 18)
    - Documentation pour les Orateurs, undated (Folder 208: 19)
    - Avant-Propos, undated (Folder 208: 20)
    - J'ai servi dans la division "Tadeusz Kosciuszko,", undated (Folder 208: 21)
    - La France et l'Europe devant le danger bolchéviste, Conférence prononcée par Paul Rezette, Référent pour la France et la Belgique de l'Antikomintern, Auslandsabteilung, à Birkenwerder devant les propagandistes français, 1944 June 7 (Folder 208: 22)
    - Le bolchévisme - Régime de Terreur, by Professor Sergej Grotow, undated (Folder 208: 23)
    - Tromperie éhontée, by Professor Grotow, undated (Folder 208: 24)
  - Part C, see box 172
  - Part D, 1938-1944
    - Sibirien, undated. (Folder 209: 1-4)
      Story told by a Volga Deutscher of life in their settlement, anti-semitic and anti-Soviet in tone. In German
    - Antibolschew. Handwörterbuch, undated. (Folder 209: 5)
      Anti-communist glossary, with emphasis on certain catchwords and personalities. In German
    - "Industrialisierung zum Verderb der Bauernschaft", undated (Folder 209: 6)
    - History of the Communist Party of Bulgaria, undated. (Folder 209: 7)
      In German
    - Miscellaneous material and intelligence reports from the Luftwaffenführungsstab, Fremde Luftwaffen Ost, 1944. (Folder 209: 8)
      In German. Photostat
    - Essay on the Soviet Union, undated. (Folder 209: 9)
    - Broschüren-Produktion, undated. (Folder 209: 10)
      Reasons for delay of publishing, such as re-editing, no paper
    - Speech on the Soviet Union, circa 1941. (Folder 209: 11)
      In German and French
    - Zum Thema "Die Sowjetunion in den Fusstapfen des Zaristischen Imperialismus,", undated (Folder 209: 12)
    - Die Arbeit der Komintern in Belgien und auf der Linie: Moskau-Skandinavien-Belgien-Paris, 0938 June 29 (Folder 209: 13)
    - Wortlaut des Briefes von Sven Hedin an Professor Kant, Rektor der Universität Dorpat, undated. (Folder 209: 14)
      Exchange of letters between Sven Hedin and Professor E. Kant
    - Bericht über Merekuela den eidesstattlichen Aussagen der, 1944 March 2. (Folder 209: 15)
      Intelligence report according to information given by a Russian political officer
    - Anti-communist excerpts from speeches by Churchill, undated. (Folder 209: 16)
    - Die Stunde ist gekommen: Russische Menschen über die UdSSR, undated (Folder 209: 17)
    - Description of Soviet labor conditions, undated. (Folder 209: 18)
      Fragments. In German
    - Unidentified fragments, undated. (Folder 209: 19)
    - Bericht der ausserordentlichen staatlichen Kommission über die Zerstörungen der deutsch-faschistischen Eroberer an industriellen, städtischen, kulturellen Anlagen im Industriegebiet von Stalin, 1943 November 13 (Folder 209: 20)
- Group IV, Printed Matter and Photographs, 1932-1944.; (6.67 linear feet) (Box 210-226)
  Printed matter, photographs, card file, and ledger.
  Arranged in groups by physical form: newspapers, bulletins and newsletters, pamphlets, articles, clippings, images, card file, oversize newspapers and magazines, and oversize ledger
  - Newspapers, 1932-1944
    - Allehanda, 1944. (Folder 210: 1)
      In Swedish
    - Au Pilori, 1944. (Folder 210: 2)
      In French
    - Aufbau Reconstruction, 1944. (Folder 210: 3)
    - Basler Nachrichten, 1944. (Folder 210: 4)
    - Brüsseler Zeitung, 1944. (Folder 210: 5)
    - Bulletin d'Information, 1944. (Folder 210: 6)
    - Central Verein Zeitung, 1938. (Folder 210: 7)
    - Daily Express, 1944. (Folder 210: 8)
      In English
    - Daily Worker, 1944. (Folder 210: 9)
    - Das Jüdische Volk, 1937. (Folder 210: 10-15)
    - Das Jüdische Volk, 1938. (Folder 211: 1-6)
    - Das Schwarze Korps, 1944. (Folder 211: 7)
    - Das Reich, undated. (Folder 211: 8)
    - Das Wochen-Ende, 1944. (Folder 211: 9)
    - Den Swenske, 1944. (Folder 211: 10)
    - Der Stürmer, 1944. (Folder 211: 11)
    - Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, 1944. (Folder 211: 12)
    - Deutsche Zeitung in den Niederlanden, 1944. (Folder 211: 13)
    - Deutsche Zeitung in Ostland, 1944. (Folder 211: 14)
    - Deutsche Zeitung in Norwegen, 1944. (Folder 211: 15)
    - Deutscher Weckruf, 1937. (Folder 211: 16)
      In German and English
    - Die Laubhütte, Deutsche Israelitische Zeitung, 1936. (Folder 211: 17)
    - Die Weltwoche, 1943. (Folder 211: 18)
    - Die Zeitung, 1944. (Folder 211: 19)
    - El Español, 1944. (Folder 211: 20)
      In Spanish
    - Gazeta Evreiasca, 1944. (Folder 211: 21)
      In Romanian
    - Gemeindeblatt, für die Jüdische Gemeinde zu Berlin, 1936. (Folder 211: 22)
    - Gemeindeblatt, für die Jüdischen Gemeinden in Rheinland und Westfalen, 1936. (Folder 211: 23)
    - Gemeinde-Zeitung, für die Israelitischen Gemeinden Württembergs, 1936. (Folder 211: 24)
    - Göteborgs Handels-Och Sjöfarts-Tidning, 1944. (Folder 211: 25)
    - Handelsteil, 1944. (Folder 211: 26)
    - Je Suis Partout, 1944. (Folder 211: 27)
    - Jewish Journal and Daily News, 1941. (Folder 212: 1-4)
      In Hebrew
    - Jüdische Rundschau, 1938. (Folder 212: 5)
    - Jüdische Zeitung, 1936. (Folder 212: 6)
    - Kölnische Zeitung, 1938. (Folder 212: 7)
    - La Gerbe, 1944. (Folder 212: 8)
    - La République, 1944. (Folder 212: 9)
    - L'Action Française, 1944. (Folder 212: 10)
    - L'Action Nationale, 1939. (Folder 212: 11)
    - L'Appel, 1944. (Folder 212: 12)
    - La France Socialiste, 1944. (Folder 212: 13)
    - Le Matin, 1944. (Folder 212: 14)
    - L'Echo de Nancy, 1944. (Folder 212: 15)
    - Le Petit Dauphinois, 1944. (Folder 212: 16)
    - La Petit Parisien, 1944. (Folder 212: 17)
    - Le Pays Réel, 1944. (Folder 213: 1)
    - Les Nouveaux Temps, 1944. (Folder 213: 2)
    - Le Journal, 1944. (Folder 213: 3)
    - L'Oeuvre, 1944. (Folder 213: 4)
    - Le Réveil du Peuple, 1944. (Folder 213: 5)
    - Mashinostroenie, 1939. (Folder 213: 6)
      In Russian
    - Nationen, 1932; 1936-1937. (Folder 213: 7)
    - Neue Leipziger Tageszeitung, 1944. (Folder 213: 8)
    - Neue Ordnung, 1944. (Folder 213: 9)
    - Neue Zürcher Zeitung, 1944. (Folder 213: 10-12)
    - News Chronicle, 1944. (Folder 213: 13)
    - Paris Midi, 1944. (Folder 213: 14)
    - Paris-soir, 1944. (Folder 213: 15)
    - Sverige Fritt, 1944. (Folder 213: 16)
    - The Daily Sketch, 1944. (Folder 213: 17)
    - The Daily Telegraph, 1944. (Folder 213: 18)
    - The Jewish Chronicle, 1943-1944. (Folder 213: 19-20)
    - The Observer, 1944. (Folder 214: 1)
    - Völkischer Beobachter, 1944. (Folder 214: 2)
  - Bulletins and newsletters, 1935-1944
    - Antikomintern Nachrichtendienst, 1943. (Folder 214: 3)
    - Auslandssttimmen für die Deutsche Wirtschaft, 1944. (Folder 213: 4)
    - Bayerische Israelitische Gemeindezeitung, 1936. (Folder 213: 5)
    - Blätter des Jüdischen Frauenbundes, 1936. (Folder 213: 6)
    - Breslauer Jüdisches Gemeindeblatt, 1936. (Folder 213: 7)
    - Der Jüdische Kantor, 1936. (Folder 213: 8)
    - Der Makkabi, 1936. (Folder 213: 9)
    - Der Deutsche Volkswirtschaft, 1944. (Folder 213: 10)
    - Gemeindeblatt Israelitischen Religionsgemeinden (Dresden), 1936. (Folder 214: 11)
    - Gemeindeblatt für den Bezirk der Synagogengemeinde Aachen, 1936. (Folder 214: 12)
    - Gemeindezeitung für den Synagogenbezirk Düsseldorf, 1936. (Folder 214: 13)
    - Königsberger Jüdisches Gemeindeblatt, 1936. (Folder 214: 14)
    - Informationen zur Judenfrage, 1944. (Folder 214: 15)
    - Informations Blätter, 1935. (Folder 214: 16)
    - Israelitisches Gemeindeblatt, 1936. (Folder 214: 17)
    - Jüdische Schulzeitung, 1936. (Folder 214: 18)
    - Kirzartikel-Dienst der Antikomintern, 1944. (Folder 214: 19)
    - Mitteilungen der Jüdischen Reformgemeinde zu Berlin, 1936. (Folder 214: 20)
    - Mitteilungen des Landesverbandes Israelitischer Religionsgemeinden Heffens, 1944. (Folder 214: 21)
    - Mitteilungsblatt, 1944. (Folder 214: 22)
    - Nachrichten aus der Sozialpolitik, 1944. (Folder 214: 23)
    - Nachrichtenblatt, 1936. (Folder 214: 24-25)
    - Nürnberg Further Isr. Gemeindeblatt, 1936. (Folder 214: 26)
    - Palästina Nachrichten, 1936. (Folder 214: 27)
    - Politische Information, 1944. (Folder 214: 28)
    - Politischer Dienst, 1944. (Folder 214: 29)
    - Reichsministerium für Volksaufklärung und Propaganda, 1944. (Folder 214: 30)
    - The Spectator, 1944. (Folder 214: 31)
    - Studien-Büro, 1944. (Folder 214: 32)
  - Pamphlets, 1943
    - Bevölkerungs- und wirstchaftspolitische Probleme der europäischen Gesamtlösung der Judenfrage, by Von Peter-Heins Seraphim, Hoheneckenverlag München, 1943 (Folder 214: 33)
  - Articles, 1934-1944 (Folder 214: 34-35)
  - Clippings, 1941-1944 (Folder 214: 36)
  - Images
    Including photographs, halftone prints, drawings, photostats, posters, and clippings
    - Miscellaneous images of people, sports, military activities, political cartoons, caricatures, etc. (Folder 215: 1-13)
    - Photographs of people in the press (Folder 215: 14-15)
    - Photographs of newspaper pages and clippings (Folder 216: 1-3)
    - Photographs of people in banking, the stock market, industry, trade, and transportation (Folder 216: 4)
    - Photographs of delinquents (Folder 216: 5)
    - Photographs of German-occupied Russia (Folder 216: 6-7)
    - Photographs and photostats of people, political cartoons, and posters. (Folder 216: 8-10)
      Includes some printed posters
    - Photographs of documents, places, people, and military activities (Folder 217: 1-5)
    - Photographs of members of the Reichsbundes jüdischer Frontsoldaten (Folder 217: 6-11)
    - Photographs of members of the Reichsbundes jüdischer Frontsoldaten (Folder 218: 1)
    - Photographs of authors and painters (Folder 218: 2-4)
    - Photographs of actors and dancers (Folder 218: 5-10)
    - Photographs of actors and dancers (Folder 219: 1)
    - Photographs of stage performances (Folder 219: 2-7)
    - Photographs of stage performances. (Folder 219: 8)
      Includes Auszüge aus Kgf. Vernehmungen Stimmung und Propaganda, 1944 January 21. Photostat
    - Photographs of scientists and physicians (Folder 219: 9-10)
    - Photographs of people in music and radio (Folder 220: 1-6)
    - Photographs of members of the Reichsbundes jüdischer Frontsoldaten (Folder 220: 7-9)
    - Photographs of members of the Reichsbundes jüdischer Frontsoldaten (Folder 221: 1-4)
    - Photographs of people (Folder 221: 5)
    - Photographs of ministers, representatives, and Berlin police officials (Folder 221: 6-10)
  - Card file of information sources concerning conferences, congresses, commission meetings, professional associations, etc. (Box 222)
    Arranged in several groups by language (primarily English, French, and German)
  - Oversize newspapers and magazines, 1929-1944
    - Gemeindeblatt, für die Jüdische Religionsgemeinde Dortmund, 1936. (Folder 223: 1)
    - Der Jüdischer Handwerker, 1936. (Folder 223: 2)
    - Neue Zeit, Bilderzeitschrift für die Deutsche Familie in Kroatien, 1944. (Folder 223: 3)
    - Les Documents Mçonniques, 1941. (Folder 223: 4)
    - Jüdisches Gemeindeblatt, Herausgegeben von der Synagogen-Gemeinde zu Danzig, 1936. (Folder 223: 5)
    - Hamburger Illustrierte, 1944. (Folder 223: 6)
    - Kladderadatsche, 1944. (Folder 223: 7)
    - L'Illustration, Frankreichs Schuld, 1940. (Folder 223: 8)
    - Die Kölnische Illustrierte Zeitung, 1944. (Folder 223: 9)
    - Gemeinde Blatt, der Judischen Gemeinde zu Berlin, 1936. (Folder 223: 10)
    - Der Adler, 1944. (Folder 223: 11)
    - Englands Schuld, Sondernummer des Illustrierten Beobachters, 1939. (Folder 223: 12)
    - De Vrijagavond, Joodsch, Weekblad, 1929-1932. (Folder 224: 1-2)
      In Dutch
    - De Vrijagavond, Joodsch, Weekblad, 1929-1932. (Folder 225: 1-2)
    - Pester Lloyd, Morgenblatt, 1944. (Folder 226: 1)
    - Volksche Aanval, 1941. (Folder 226: 2)
      In Flemish
    - Volksverwering, 1940-1941. (Folder 226: 3)
    - L'Ami du Peuple, 1941. (Folder 226: 4)
  - Oversize ledger, 1938-1940
    Contains entries for individuals, organizations, and publications, with daily expense columns and monthly totals.
    Arranged by month, thereunder roughly alphabetically by name or place and name, such as "Dr. Frank" and "Wien, Zeitungsdienst"